<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Reality Improvement</title><link href="http://www.realityimprovement.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.realityimprovement.com/feeds/blog/website-happenings.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.realityimprovement.com/</id><updated>2014-06-16T10:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Site Re-Relaunch</title><link href="http://www.realityimprovement.com/2014/June/site-re-relaunch/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-16T10:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Alistair</name></author><id>tag:www.realityimprovement.com,2014-06-16:2014/June/site-re-relaunch/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The best of intentions do not amount to anything without action. The "relaunch"
was not a success. Obviously. This is the first post I've made since the site
went live on Github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part (and only part, I still have some motivation and procrastination issues to
deal with) of the problem is that I've never really defined what I wanted this 
site, and especially the blog part of the site, to be. Despite reading many 
blogs, and the advice about starting blogs and gaining a readership (and what's 
the point of this if not to gain readers, I can keep a journal for myself 
without half as much effort) I was unwillingy to accept the facts. Successful 
sites, for the most part, have a narrow focus to them, and a regular update
schedule. I wanted this site to be everything, without really defining what 
"everything" is to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Focused Site Plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Blog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be a blog post every Sunday evening (local time to wherever I am)
(Also I'm quite aware this is being posted Monday morning, baby steps). The blog
is turning into a dedicated travel blog, consisting of trip reports and stories
inspired from my travels. Alternatively there may be site update post similar
to this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general the posts will be short, light hearted reads. I'll try to have some
photos and maybe a drawing or two. This focus has dual purpose. Defining what
the blog is about. But also forcing me to have experinces in real life. A blog
of my musings and thoughts like the site has been so far just isn't that 
inspiring to write, mostly because I don't think I'm that interesting of a 
person. Weekly stories about travel, adventure and new activities forces me out 
of my shell, and my house, to grow and become more interesting. And experience 
this world, which can be pretty damn fascinating at times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Comic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the back of my mind has been stirring the idea for a story based comic based
on the name of the site. So this Wednesday evening, and every Wednesday after 
that I will be posting a page of my new Comic: RIB, the Reality Improvement 
Bureau. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The One Shot comics that were the original idea of this site will continue, but
(beware danger of never getting done) they won't have a fixed update schedule. 
(For now.) I didn't choose the name of the site to start a comic with that name.
But I like the idea so I'm going to run with it for now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again a fixed schedule is the most important part of this. The only way I'll 
commit, is to have a commitment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Feature: Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I'm not willing to give up totally on the idea of this being a general space
for everything I'm thinking. But I want it to be more structured. So on the 
final Friday of each month I'm going to write a more detailed post, more of 
an article than a blog post. They will be focused on a specific topic and have
research and such. The first topic I'm working
on is personal, about procrastinaiton, laziness and working hard. That may sound
contradictory but hopefully I can coalesce it into something meaningfull by the 
end of the month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some ways they are a vanity project, but I no longer want to put just general
musings on this site. I don't like posting in public all the thoughts I have and
so I censor myself and post things I'm not happy with or I don't post. 
But I don't mind being public for specific reasons. The
travel blog may get personal but will be usually as a result of humour, something
I'm quite willing to be vulnerable for. These posts may also get personal, but
hopefully it will be as an educational or enlightening experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goals and The Future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that's it. To start off with three specfic tasks. The comic, the original
intention of the site. The blog, now a travel blog, what the site has kind of
evolved into. The Articles, a way to educate myself about topics I'm interested
in or are personally important to me. But that's it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the long run I'm still interested in adding videos to the site, but not until
the other three things are established. And once the new comic is up and being 
updated regularly I want to look at maybe other ideas. Despite the new focus, I 
never intendted for this website to be a just single comic. It is still an outlet
for most of my creative endeavours, just a little more realistic in scope. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it's a bit of a cop out to start this with another "Website Happenings" post
rather than an actual travel post, which would have been more appropriate and 
shown actual dedication. But I only came up with this plan on Sunday afternoon 
and I only remembered a commitment for Sunday Evening at the last minute. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Plans"></category><category term="Dates"></category><category term="News"></category><category term="Travel"></category><category term="Comic"></category></entry><entry><title>Site Relaunch</title><link href="http://www.realityimprovement.com/2014/February/site-relaunch/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-02-03T13:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alistair</name></author><id>tag:www.realityimprovement.com,2014-02-03:2014/February/site-relaunch/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been quite a while since an update. I had just left Charlotte bound for
the West Coast. I ultimately didn't make it to San Fransisco. I will make a blog
post soon about all that happend for the rest of the trip. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for now I've finished up my adventures in America. I've been in the UK for
two months. There were no blog posts for a few reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turned out to be very difficult to update while driving alone cross-country.
At the end of each day, I was very tired. Also I spent quite a few nights driving
till late and then I would park in a rest stop for the night. No chance to get
the laptop out on those days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wordpress install broke. An autoupdate broke the plugin and
theme I was using to power the comic part of this website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number 2 could have been a rather quick fix, but I'd already been getting a bit
fed up with wordpress anyway. So I started looking at alternatives. I'm 
familiar with the python programming language so I was looking for python alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with Django and looking at the various cms' built on that. Mezzanine
seemed large and bloated but the best choice, especially as it had the best
Python 3 support. But before I'd gotten very far into that, I chanced across
a new movement that is sweeping the blogs of technically minded bloggers. Static
site generators. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Static site generators take your content, articles, pages etc. and convert it
straight into html. No php, no database to worry about, 
nothing dynamic that is generated server side. 
This leads to fast, secure websites that can be hosted almost anywhere. 
I've even moved this website to github, which allows hosting of static websites. 
This is free and faster than my old hosting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many static site generators out there, written in almost any language
you can think of. Github even has one built in written in ruby. But as I'm 
familiar with python I looked into python versions. Settling on pelican, as it
has the largest community behind it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been a great, if slow learning experience. Through porting my website over
I've been relearning how to code, something I haven't done in a while. I'm now
officially an open source contributor, having coded up three plugins and altering
a fourth to get all the functionality I had with wordpress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the website is back. Expect more travel posts. But more importantly, expect
more comics as well. The site will still be going through some cosmetic changes
over the next few weeks. I've been brushing up on my css skills and learning all
the new html5 stuff. This may lead to a junior web design job, or some freelance
work. Something I can do on the road if I need to so I can start travelling again.
It would be great to land some acting work but if I don't this would be something
versatile and creative, and let me live a digital nomad lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Wordpress"></category><category term="Pelican"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="Travel"></category><category term="USA"></category><category term="UK"></category><category term="London"></category></entry><entry><title>Hey, look at that</title><link href="http://www.realityimprovement.com/2012/May/hey-look-at-that/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-23T01:54:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Alistair</name></author><id>tag:www.realityimprovement.com,2012-05-23:2012/May/hey-look-at-that/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;that there, in the url bar/tab. A new favicon. That's what I did to the
website today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also the Jetpack plugin is bad, and blocks things. Any problems you have
with the media pages should be gone now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the media page; I somehow performed the popcorn song at an
open mic night tonight. That was a little odd. Was much better received
than it had any right to be.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Music"></category><category term="Wordpress"></category></entry><entry><title>Media Page</title><link href="http://www.realityimprovement.com/2011/December/media-page/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-12-09T12:45:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Alistair</name></author><id>tag:www.realityimprovement.com,2011-12-09:2011/December/media-page/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href="media"&gt;media link&lt;/a&gt; in the side bar. I've uploaded a video
and a song so far, hopefully with more to come.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Wordpress"></category></entry><entry><title>Now it's a website</title><link href="http://www.realityimprovement.com/2011/September/now-its-a-website/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-09-27T00:15:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Alistair</name></author><id>tag:www.realityimprovement.com,2011-09-27:2011/September/now-its-a-website/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I have wasted enough time making the site presentable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spent the last couple of days just playing with the layout and CSS.
There's still a few niggly things that annoy me but I've definitely
reached the point where I can walk away from it and be happy. It's
simple and clean and that's good enough for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now; make the things happen time.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Wordpress"></category></entry><entry><title>Welcome</title><link href="http://www.realityimprovement.com/2011/September/ignore-this-for-now/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-09-13T15:18:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Alistair</name></author><id>tag:www.realityimprovement.com,2011-09-13:2011/September/ignore-this-for-now/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello there,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You've landed on this page which means you're probably someone I know.
Hey you, sorry we haven't talked in so long, we should definitely catch
up soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, enjoy the ride, ridicule me harshly. Updates will be sporadic
but I'll try to keep them semi-frequent. But hopefully by me putting
this up and welcoming you all it becomes something I do, rather than
something I don't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alistair&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Wordpress"></category></entry></feed>